Hello, there.
大家好
My name is Sacha Guddoy
我叫Sacha Guddoy
and I'm the lead Front End Engineer at Grabyo. slide-2
是Grabyo的首席前端工程师 slide-2
Grabyo is a SaaS platform which delivers tools
Grabyo是一个SaaS平台
for live broadcast production to commercial broadcasters. 6-p
向商业广播公司提供直播制作工具 6-p
Some of our offerings include live broadcast production,
我们的一些服务包括直播制作
video editing, clipping from live streams,
视频编辑 从直播流中剪辑
and publishing to various endpoints. slide-3
以及发布到各种终端 slide-3
At Grabyo, we use WebRTC in our live production offering. 10-p
我们在Grabyo提供的直播制作服务中使用了WebRTC 10-p
The way that this works is the user will see,
其工作方式是 用户会看到
in their web browser,
在他们的web浏览器中
they'll have multiple live streams coming in
会显示多个直播流输入
and they will be able to monitor these live streams
他们能够监控这些直播流
and choose which ones are being output
并选择哪些流输出至
to their broadcast endpoint. 16-p
他们的广播终端 16-p
We also have multiple sidecar applications
我们也有多个Sidecar模式应用
and multi-window workflows.
和多窗口的工作流
For example, popping out a player. slide-4
例如 弹出一个播放器 slide-4
One of the challenges that we face is
我们面临的一个挑战
the synchronization of streams. 21-p
就是直播流的同步 21-p
What we'd like to do is to have multiple live feeds
我们想做的是同时输入多个
from different cameras coming in
来自不同摄像机的直播画面
and to be able to switch between them.
并能在它们之间切换
But if our live feeds aren't perfectly in sync
但是 如果我们的直播画面
with each other,
不是完全同步的
if those two cameras aren't perfectly in sync,
如果有两台摄像机不是完全同步的
it's going to be very noticeable when
当你在它们之间切换时
you switch between them that there's some delay
会很明显地发现它们之间有一些延迟
between them and it's jarring for the viewer. 30-p
这对观众来说是难以忍受的 30-p
When you have multiple WebRTC streams on your page,
当你的页面上有多个WebRTC流时
keeping those all in sync is not necessarily
要保持这些流的同步
the most straightforward thing.
没有那么简单
The browser will do its best, but they aren't tied together. 34-p
浏览器会尽力而为 但这些流并未绑定 34-p
So, for example,
举例来说
if you are cutting between different cameras,
如果你在不同的摄像头之间切换
you want those camera feeds to be showing exactly
你希望这些摄像头的画面
at the same time.
能完全在同一时间显示
If you're doing multi-party chat, you don't want latency. slide-5
如果你要进行多人聊天 你不希望有延迟 slide-5
The synchronization aspect is pretty difficult.
同步方面是相当困难的
Network conditions can be unpredictable
网络条件可能难以预测
and you don't really have a way of correcting for that
你没有办法纠正这一点
or to reconcile with synchronization of streams
也没有办法与客户端的流同步
on the client side. 44-p
进行协调 44-p
If there were embedded time stamps on the streams,
如果在数据流上有嵌入式的时间戳
then you potentially could do that.
那么你就有可能做到这一点
Using something lower level, such as Web Transport,
使用较底层的技术 如WebTransport
may allow you to do that
可能会助你实现这一点
and may even be a more performant technology
甚至与WebRTC相比
for this use case than WebRTC anyway. slide-6
这种技术可能更适合这种用例 slide-6
One pattern that we've been using recently is
我们最近一直在使用的一种模式
splitting workflows into different browser contexts.
是将工作流程分割成不同的浏览器上下文
Being able to create a pop out window
能够创建一个弹出式窗口
which allows you to monitor
允许你在一个窗口中监控
a specific video in one window
某个特定的视频
and be able to monitor everything else in another window. 56-p
并能够在另一个窗口中监控其他一切 56-p
Or to be able to edit your audio in one window
或者能够在一个窗口中编辑你的音频
and monitor your videos in another window.
同时在另一个窗口中监控你的视频
In that last scenario, you're going to be having
在最后一种场景中 你将在浏览器中
two instances in your browser
拥有同一个WebRTC连接的
of that same WebRTC connection.
两个实例
If I wanted to have the video of my live stream
如果我想在一个窗口中看到直播视频流
in one window because that's my video control suite
因为那是我的视频控制套件
and I want to have the same live stream in another window
同时我想在另一个窗口看到同样的视频流
because that's my audio control suite,
因为那是我的音频控制套件
then I have to have two WebRTC connections.
那么我必须有两个WebRTC连接
That's twice the performance overhead,
这是两倍的性能开销
twice the bandwidth, et cetera. 68-p
两倍的带宽 以此类推 68-p
We think about the way that Shared WebWorkers work,
我们考虑了Shared WebWorkers的工作方式
the SharedWorker itnerface,
即SharedWorker接口
that allows multiple contexts to share whatever
它允许多个上下文共享该Worker中
is happening in that Worker.
发生的任何事件
If we could do the exact same thing with WebRTC,
如果我们能用WebRTC做同样的事情
that would significantly reduce our performance overhead. 74-p
这将大大减少我们的性能开销 74-p
And these kinds of workflows are really powerful
这类工作流对于专业的桌面应用来说
for professional desktop applications.
真的很强大
If you are a video editor using some kind of NLE,
如果你是使用非线性剪辑软件的视频编辑
you probably want as much screen space as you want
你可能想要分配尽可能多的屏幕空间
for your timeline, your monitors,
给你的时间线 你的显示器
your asset bins, et cetera.
你的资源库 等等
Being able to kind of split different parts
能够将我们界面各部分分割成不同的窗口
of our interfaces out into different windows
以便用户能够
so the user can position them as they see fit
按照他们认为合适的方式定位
is really, really helpful. slide-7
这大有裨益 slide-7
What are the advantages of doing this? 85-p
那么这样做有什么好处呢？ 85-p
There's obviously less resource consumption
很明显 资源消耗减少了
because you only have that one connection. 87-p
因为你只需要一个连接 87-p
There's inherent synchronization between the contexts
上下文之间有内在的同步性
because the data is coming from that same connection.
因为数据来自同一个连接
Now this is probably possible using shared workers
现在有可能使用Shared WebWorkers
and Web Transport.
和WebTransport来实现这一点
But browser support for that is not particularly great. 92-p
但浏览器对它的支持并不是特别好 92-p
Accuracy is also important in this technology.
准确性在这项技术中也很重要
More accurate time stamps might help us
更准确的时间戳可能有助于我们
synchronize those streams together.
将这些数据流同步起来
And also it helps synchronize other things. 96-p
而且还有助于同步其他东西 96-p
For example, synchronize an overlay in the DOM.
例如 在DOM中同步显示一个图层
Or a notification in the DOM. slide-8
或者一条通知 slide-8
Capability to encode and decode data
对来自WebRTC连接的数据
from a WebRTC connection would also be really useful. 100-p
进行编码和解码的能力也会非常有用 100-p
Right now, the API surface of
目前WebRTC连接的API接口
the WebRTC connection is pretty minimal
功能十分有限
and it doesn't expose much useful information to us.
它无法让我们获取太多有用的信息
Being able to put our own code in that pipeline
如果能够把我们自己的代码放在该流程中
would allow us to do all this interesting stuff. 105-p
我们就能够实现所有这些有趣的功能 105-p
Say, for example, presenting a particular frame
比如说 在我们需要的时候
when we want to present it.
展示某帧特定的画面
Say, for example, synchronizing audio and video
再比如说 从不同的浏览器窗口
from different browser windows. 109-p
同步音频和视频 109-p
We could know exactly which frame is being presented
我们可以在它们被渲染至DOM之前
before they even get rendered to the DOM,
准确地知道正在显示的是哪一帧
so we can prepare our DOM elements
这样一来我们就可以提前准备DOM元素
which would synchronize to that.
使其与之同步
We could potentially send over
我们将能够发送
proprietary error correction data
专有的纠错数据
to smooth over any link failures
来修复任何以图像质量为优先的
with picture quality as a priority. 117-p
链接故障 117-p
And going back the other way,
从另一个角度看
you could do stuff like funny hats.
你可以给人像添加帽饰
You could do chroma keying.
你可以实现抠像
You could do machine learning analysis
你可以做机器学习分析
and do stuff like background blur
以及像是背景模糊
or embedding metadata. 123-p
或者嵌入元数据之类的 123-p
A lot of this can be solved using
这方面的很多问题
the MediaStreamTrack Insertable Streams feature.
都可以用MediaStreamTrack的可插入流功能来解决
That is still in a draft specification
它目前还只是一项规范草案
and I'd really love to see more browser support for that. 127-p
我真的希望更多的浏览器能支持这一功能 127-p
Thank you for watching.
感谢大家的观看
I hope you enjoyed hearing about our use cases
希望我们介绍的用例能带来启发
and I'm looking forward to hearing
我很期待收到
any questions and feedback.
任何问题和反馈
Thanks, bye.
谢谢 再见